JONATHAN MANOA

Santa Maria, California · 805-345-5168 j.manoa1570@gmail.com · github.com/j-manoa1570 · linkedin.com/in/jonathan-manoa

SUMMARY

People oriented Computer scientist seeking challenging, new opportunities to solve real world problems and develop additional skills and innovative techniques to benefit team. 3+ years of experience in management. Experienced in building web APIs, mobile development, and familiar with embedded systems with a strong interest in hardware/software interactions and project management.

EDUCATION

SEPTEMBER 2014 - APRIL 2019

BACHELOR'S IN COMPUTER SCIENCE, BRIGHAM YOUNG UNIVERSITY – IDAHO, REXBURG ID

Relevant Coursework: Embedded Systems (3 semesters), Discrete Math (4 semesters), Web Development (backend), Data Structures, Software Design and Development (design patterns and an Android app), Software Engineering (3 semesters, development methodologies and risk mitigation, Software Requirements Specification and Software Design Description documents, and project estimation).

SKILLS

- Languages: C/C++, Java, Swift, Python, JavaScript, Lisp(familiar), Bash scripting(familiar)
- Development Tools: VS Code, IntelliJ Idea, XCode, GitHub
- Operating Systems: OSX, Windows, Linux
- Soft Skills: Communication, teamwork, problem-solving, leadership

EXPERIENCE

PERSONAL DEVELOPMENT

- Researched, designed, developed, and tested an Arduino based module to wirelessly control DMX fixtures by BLE from iOS application for small scale productions.
- Learned Swift language, iOS development, BLE usage and protocol, Arduino data protocols UART and SPI, and DMX protocol on own.

JUNE 2019 - PRESENT

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT INTERN, THROUGH THE MAZE

- Researched, designed, and developed specifications for API to automate the process of exporting and updating customer records on SignalVine platform from company website.
- Programmed, Installed, and managed API on local Raspberry Pi tomcat server for testing which included https/ssl and certificate installation and validation and an AWS Elastic Beanstalk instance for API deployment.
- Provide technical support and guidance to company owners to reduce costs from 3rd party tools.

 Developed skills in technical documentation, namely various UML diagrams, self-documenting and welldocumented code, and writing API documentation for users to successfully use API.

SEPTEMBER 2016 – AUGUST 2018

LIGHTING TECHNICIAN, ANDX ENTERTAINMENT

- Designed and setup lighting rigs with 30+ fixtures.
- Ran light shows and live video mixing during various events including college parties, conventions, weddings, and high school dance.
- Lead a team of 2-6, effectively communicating expectations and vision for events creating little to no downtime during setups and teardowns.

SEPTEMBER 2016 - AUGUST 2018

STAGE CREW, ANDX ENTERTAINMENT

- First choice for being contracted out to other production companies at locations such at The Salt Palace (Salt Lake City, UT), Maverick Stadium (Logan UT), and Portneuf Health Trust Amphitheatre (Pocatello ID) for acts such as Lynyrd Skynyrd, Stone Temple Pilots, Old Dominion, and Montgomery Gentry.
- Setup and teardown of stage, lighting and video rigs, sound equipment, musical equipment without need for supervision or guidance to complete tasks.

NOVEMBER 2015 – JULY 2017

ASSISTANT TEAM LEAD, BYU-IDAHO COURSE SUPPORT

- Maintained, fixed, and improved 200+ courses through BYU-I online education program.
- Worked alongside on-campus and adjunct faculty to resolve technical issues and provide a better online learning experience for instructors and students.
- Assisted in additional hands-on training of employees across Brainhoney and Brightspace learning systems to ensure higher quality and more efficient fixes.
- Quality checked team members tickets for proper fixes testing to ensure no problems have been introduced while resolving current technical issue.

OCTOBER 2006 - MARCH 2010

SENIOR CENTER SPECIALIST, FEDEX OFFICE

- Created, designed, and produced costumer orders with precision to meet and exceed customer expectations. Designed projects for include DenMat, IMPO International, Costco, and 7-11's along the coast of California.
- Effectively managed and produced on average 10-15 jobs during shift while increasing store's Done Right and On Time score.
- Provided hands-on training on all in-house and outsourced machines and services to new employees.
- Day/Night and Weekend supervisor over a team of 3-5 employees.